<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bio-Team Development</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bio-Team Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:34:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2-2: Assignment 1 Review and Coordinate Reference Systems</title>
      <link>/2020/08/31/2-2-assignment-1-review-and-coordinate-reference-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/31/2-2-assignment-1-review-and-coordinate-reference-systems/</guid>
      <description>OverviewThis week we will go over the script that we developed last session. We will address someof the questions from last week’s assignment and go over the projection issue encounteredin the toy data set. Let’s dive in!
Today’s Assignment – Looking at North Carolina County Data: Part IIYou will need:The script you wrote last weekPost-work beverage of choicePart 1: Script and Questions ReviewOpen RStudio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-1: Welcome to Arc 2 - Programmatic Geospatial Analysis</title>
      <link>/2020/08/17/2-1-welcome-to-arc-2-programmatic-geospatial-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/17/2-1-welcome-to-arc-2-programmatic-geospatial-analysis/</guid>
      <description>We’re Back – and Interactive!Welcome to the second round of Bio-Group trainings. In this series, we will expand ourGIS and problem-solving toolkits by leveraging the power of computation. To this end,we will use the R programming language and some important associated geospatial packages.Let’s dive in!
A Brief introduction to the R Programming LanguageSuccinctly, R is free software designed for statisticalcomputing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing It All Together</title>
      <link>/2020/06/01/bringing-it-all-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/01/bringing-it-all-together/</guid>
      <description>So What’s It All Been About?We’ve done a lot over the past 4 training sessions, so let’s review what we’ve done. I’ll briefly summarize what we’ve done, and in the process will generate for us a tidy little Rmarkdown report in which we can see how far we have come. Links to the original blog posts for each session are linked to in the title of each section, where you can view the full code and the breakdown of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Predictive Models of COVID-19 Cases</title>
      <link>/2020/05/11/generating-predictive-models-of-covid-19-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/11/generating-predictive-models-of-covid-19-cases/</guid>
      <description>To view and download the code and run it yourself, head on over to the GitHub site
library(data.table)library(sf)library(RPostgreSQL)library(magrittr)library(randomForest)library(Metrics)library(ggplot2)library(keras)library(tensorflow)# devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;rstudio/keras&amp;quot;)git.path &amp;lt;- Sys.getenv(&amp;#39;HOME&amp;#39;) # Where the base COVID19-Data-Exploration folder lives.##---------------------------------------------------------------## Read In Data and Munge --##---------------------------------------------------------------# read in and munge Michael&amp;#39;s dataad_col_names &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#39;State&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;pop_dense&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;sh_date&amp;#39;)ad &amp;lt;- fread(file.path(git.path,&amp;quot;Code/COVID19-Data-Exploration/data/Pop_Density_By_State.csv&amp;quot;))ad &amp;lt;- ad[,c(&amp;#39;State:&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Pop Density per square mile&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Stay at home order date enacted:&amp;#39;)]colnames(ad) &amp;lt;- ad_col_namesad$sh_date &amp;lt;- format(as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping COVID-19 Cases in Oregon</title>
      <link>/2020/04/27/mapping-covid-19-cases-in-oregon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/27/mapping-covid-19-cases-in-oregon/</guid>
      <description>Session OverviewThis week, Kelsey spent some time mapping the COVID-19 cases in Oregon and generated some plots forus. She already has provided some most illustrative documentation for her code, so I will simplyattempt to augment what she has already done.
In this post, we will be covering the following subjects:
Subsetting the full dataset to obtain only the Oregon casesDividing the Oregon data into 10-day intervals for analysisGenerating a 2-dimensional density plot (heatmap) of the confirmed cases in OregonAs always, if you’d like to download the code and run it yourself, check it out on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Databases</title>
      <link>/2020/04/13/an-introduction-to-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/13/an-introduction-to-databases/</guid>
      <description>Session OverviewThis week as part of the series, Kyle introduced us to some basic database managementby moving the csv data that we dowloaded from the JHU CSSE database to a local PostgresSQL instance onhis machine and demoing some simple commands. The main updates to the code in thesession were:
Instead of downloading every csv from the John’s Hopkins database every time werun the script, only the most recent csv files (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:34:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This site will host the blogposts associated with the Bio-group Development Series sessions. The site theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Download and Sanitation (and our first plot!)</title>
      <link>/2020/03/30/data-download-and-sanitation-and-our-first-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/30/data-download-and-sanitation-and-our-first-plot/</guid>
      <description>March 30, 2020Hello, and welcome to a summary of the first training session for bio-group technicaldevelopment! This is an Rmarkdown document that will walk you through what wedid in the first session on March 30, 2020. Here we will download the data from theJHU CSSE database and plot thereported confirmed cases, deaths, and recoveries for a country of interestsince January 22, 2020.
LibrariesAt the top of any script we write, first we include all the libraries used in thisanalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Bio-Group Development Series</title>
      <link>/2020/03/30/welcome-to-the-bio-group-development-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/30/welcome-to-the-bio-group-development-series/</guid>
      <description>Welcome!Hello everyone, and welcome to the website for the Bio-Group Development Series! Here wewill publish blog posts related to the various Monday-evening trainings as wellas resources for you to further delve into to the topics covered. In this firstset of trainings, we are looking at some data on the spread of COVID-19 virus, asexplained below.
COVID-19 DatasetWith the myriad statistics of the novel coronavirus pervading most media outlets,we opted to examine the data ourselves to obtain a clearer understanding of thespread of the disease.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>